Wilton Historical Society Printed Matter Collection
Wilton History Room, Wilton Historical Society
- 8. Town of Wilton
  - Celebrations and observances
    - Wilton: A Celebration of Vision and Values, 1993; Video. (Cabinet 8, Folder 582)
    - "Wilton Dearest" - Programs, 1990-1996 (Cabinet 8, Folder 590)
  - Chamber of Commerce
    - "All About Wilton", undated; See also Wilton Business Directory. (Cabinet 8, Folder 202)
    - Charter, 1992 (Cabinet 8, Folder 206)
    - Children's Center - Wilton Y - Day care, 1984 (Cabinet 8, Folder 208)
    - Miscellaneous, undated; See also Wilton Business Directory. (Cabinet 8, Folder 201)
    - Newsletters, 1990-2005; File 203a covers 1990-1995; file 203b covers 1996-1999; file 203c covers 2000-2004; file 203d covers 2005 and beyond. (Cabinet 8, Folder 203a, 203b, 203c, 203d)
    - Survey, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 204)
  - Charter and codes
    - Code of ethics, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 509b)
    - Code of town, 1993 (Cabinet 8, Folder 509c)
    - Town of Wilton - Charter, 1968-1969; File 290 covers 1968-1969; file 291 covers 1962. (Cabinet 8, Folder 290, 291)
  - Conservation Commission
    - Newsletters, 1982-2000; File 303a covers 1982-1999; file 303b covers 2000 and beyond. (Cabinet 8, Folder 303a, 303b)
    - Open space brochure, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 304a)
    - "Open Space Preserves of Wilton", undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 304b)
    - Preservation list of Connecticut wild plants, 1987 (Cabinet 8, Folder 304c)
    - Wilton trail guide, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 304c)
    - Wilton wetlands, undated; See also Planning, "Land Use Q & A Guide." (Cabinet 8, Folder 304d)
  - Fire Department
    - Annual report, 1975-1979 (Cabinet 8, Folder 313)
    - Georgetown Volunteer Fire Company, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 314a)
    - Wilton Fire Department, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 314b)
    - Wilton Minstrel Show - Program, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 314c)
    - Wilton Volunteer Fire Department, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 314d)
  - Guidebooks and local history
    - 100 Things to Do, 1991-1995 (Cabinet 8, Folder 520)
    - Earle, Morris - "Nutty Nutmegs: Better Guide to Connecticut Towns", 1963 (Cabinet 8, Folder 302b)
    - Getting to Know Wilton, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 545)
    - Guide to historic attractions, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 547)
    - Heritage, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 550)
    - Historical Society, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 555)
    - Real estate brochure, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 416)
    - Restaurant and dining guide, 1970-1974 (Cabinet 8, Folder 513c)
    - "Wilton: A Celebration of Vision and Values", undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 518)
    - Wilton: A Rural Town near Metropolitan New York, 1939 (Cabinet 8, Folder 575)
    - Wilton Answer Book, 1994-2002; File 580 covers 1994-2001; file 581 covers 2002 and beyond. (Cabinet 8, Folder 580, 581)
    - Wilton - Board of Realtors brochure, circa1983 (Cabinet 8, Folder 573)
    - Your Guide to Norwalk, Darien, New Canaan and Wilton, 1976 (Cabinet 8, Folder 572)
  - Housing
    - "Affordable Housing" - Fairfield County, 1980 (Cabinet 8, Folder 327)
    - Housing needs - Assessment, 1988 (Cabinet 8, Folder 328)
    - "Need for Additional Moderate Income Housing in Wilton", 1985 (Cabinet 8, Folder 329a)
    - Poor house, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 399b)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Community center, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 301)
    - Community portrait, 1979 (Cabinet 8, Folder 302a)
    - Historic District and Historic Property Committee of Wilton, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 325)
    - Hunting licenses, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 340b)
    - Post office, 1983 (Cabinet 8, Folder 402)
  - Parks and open spaces
    - Ambler farm, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 368)
    - Bradley Park - Trail guide, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 370)
    - Devil’s Den - Trail and field guides, 1977-1985 (Cabinet 8, Folder 372)
    - Guide to Wilton's parks, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 375)
    - Long range plan, 1967 (Cabinet 8, Folder 376)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 373)
    - Open Space Public Act 490, 1976 (Cabinet 8, Folder 364)
    - Parks and recreation programs, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 380)
    - Walker's Guide to the Wilton Area, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 378)
    - Woodcock Nature Center, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 379)
  - Planning and zoning
    - "A Multi-family Development Proposal", 1971 (Cabinet 8, Folder 390)
    - Amendment to the Comprehensive Plan of Development, 1974 (Cabinet 8, Folder 393c)
    - "Community Facilities Program", 1970 (Cabinet 8, Folder 389b)
    - "Comprehensive Plan of Development", 1973 (Cabinet 8, Folder 392)
    - "Comprehensive Plan: Recreation, Conservation, Open Space", 1967 (Cabinet 8, Folder 387)
    - Emergency Operations Plan, 1975 (Cabinet 8, Folder 510)
    - "Existing Land Use Report", 1971 (Cabinet 8, Folder 391)
    - Land Subdivision Regulations, 1972 (Cabinet 8, Folder 512b)
    - "Land Subdivision Regulations of the Planning Committee", 1961 (Cabinet 8, Folder 385b)
    - "Land Use Questions and Answer Guide", 2002 (Cabinet 8, Folder 398a)
    - "Municipal Facilities Feasibility Study", 1979 (Cabinet 8, Folder 513a)
    - "Open Space Plan", 1983 (Cabinet 8, Folder 395)
    - "Planning in Wilton", 1974 (Cabinet 8, Folder 393a)
    - "Plan of Conservation and Development 1996 Revised", 1999 (Cabinet 8, Folder 397b)
    - "Plan of Conservation and Development", 1996 (Cabinet 8, Folder 397a)
    - "Proposed Amendments to the Plan of Development", 1987 (Cabinet 8, Folder 396)
    - "Report on Problems and Objectives", 1954 (Cabinet 8, Folder 385a)
    - Sewer Authority, 1974 (Cabinet 8, Folder 514)
    - "Toward the Region of the Future", 1974 (Cabinet 8, Folder 393b)
    - "Town Plan of Development", 1963 (Cabinet 8, Folder 386)
    - Wilton 1954: A Report on Problems and Objectives (Cabinet 8, Folder 517)
    - "Wilton Center Area Plan", 1969 (Cabinet 8, Folder 389a)
    - "Wilton Center Plan", 1969-1976 (Cabinet 8, Folder 587)
    - "Wilton Center Plan", 1976 (Cabinet 8, Folder 394)
    - "Your Town", 1951 (Cabinet 8, Folder 384)
    - "Your Town: Report of Town Planning Committee", 1951 (Cabinet 8, Folder 519)
    - Zoning Regulations, 1946-2001; File 595 covers 1946-1966; file 596 covers 1972-1988; file 598 covers 1994-2001. (Cabinet 8, Folder 595, 596, 598)
  - Politics and voters
    - Democrat campaigning, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 398b)
    - Electors list - Democrats, 1949 (Cabinet 8, Folder 309a)
    - Electors list - Republicans, 1949 (Cabinet 8, Folder 309b)
    - Electors list - Town of Wilton, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 309c)
    - Handbook for Voters of Wilton, 1943 (Cabinet 8, Folder 522a)
    - Republican Club dinner, 1904 (Cabinet 8, Folder 399a)
  - Reports and surveys
    - Annual report, 1886 (Cabinet 8, Folder 508b)
    - Committees and rules of the General Assembly of Connecticut, 1903 (Cabinet 8, Folder 320)
    - Disposition of public lands, 1839 (Cabinet 8, Folder 318)
    - General information and statistics, 1994 (Cabinet 8, Folder 511b)
    - "Inventory of Town Owned Properties", 1975 (Cabinet 8, Folder 512a)
    - Mather Street lands, 1987 (Cabinet 8, Folder 512c)
    - Noise survey - Wilton Transfer Station, 1981 (Cabinet 8, Folder 513ab)
    - Property evaluation, 1994 (Cabinet 8, Folder 513b)
    - "Rules of General Assembly", 1903 (Cabinet 8, Folder 323a)
    - Selectmen's progress reports, 1970-1975; File 3221 covers 1970-1975. (Cabinet 8, Folder 322a, 513d)
    - Statistics of Connecticut state officers - May session, 1854 (Cabinet 8, Folder 322b)
    - Summary of official actions, 1970-1974 (Cabinet 8, Folder 322aa)
    - "The Town Government - Wilton", 1961 (Cabinet 8, Folder 323b)
    - "Town Government", 1961 (Cabinet 8, Folder 516)
    - "Wilton - A Study of Its Town Government", 1958 (Cabinet 8, Folder 323)
    - Wilton annual reports, undated; See also Pamphlets. (Cabinet 8, Folder 574)
  - Roads and transportation
    - Intersection improvements in Wilton, 1997 (Cabinet 8, Folder 521b)
    - Local intersections - Study, 1987 (Cabinet 8, Folder 521a)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 440)
    - Route 7 - Southern connector road - Study, 1979 (Cabinet 8, Folder 443)
    - Route 7 - Studies, 1959-1994; File 442a covers 1959-1961; file 442b covers 1971-1976; file 442c covers 1982-1994. (Cabinet 8, Folder 442a, 442b, 442c)
  - Seniors and senior housing
    - Senior center, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 475)
    - Senior center - Newsletters, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 476a)
    - Senior housing - Development plan, 2000 (Cabinet 8, Folder 476a)
    - Senior services, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 513e)
    - The Greens, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 476b)
  - Taxes and finance
    - Financial planning, 1959-1971 (Cabinet 8, Folder 511a)
    - Future financial needs and resources, 1959 (Cabinet 8, Folder 511ab)
    - Tax collector notices, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 571)
    - Tax records and directory, 1942-1967 (Cabinet 8, Folder 503a)
    - Tax records based on Grand List, 1938-1966; Lists are for 1938-1940, 1945, 1950, 1955, and 1966. (Cabinet 8, Folder 515a)
    - Taxes, 1913-1942 (Cabinet 8, Folder 515b)
  - Water and wetlands
    - Georgetown - Water quality, 1999 (Cabinet 8, Folder 317b)
    - Norwalk River watershed, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 350d)
    - Wetland and water courses - Regulations, 1973-1993 (Cabinet 8, Folder 528)
    - Wilton wetlands, 1978 (Cabinet 8, Folder 529)
- 9. War and veterans
  - Miscellaneous
    - Aircraft identification, 1942; World War Two. (Cabinet 8, Folder 102)
    - Civil defense, 1941; World War Two. (Cabinet 8, Folder 280)
    - "Crusade Canal Code - 310 Signal Operation Battalion", undated; Brochure. (Cabinet 8, Folder 522c)
    - "Joseph A. Hopkins: His Flag Flew Over Iwo Jima", 1951; World War Two. (Cabinet 8, Folder 522b)
    - Tribute to Wilton veterans, 2001 (Cabinet 8, Folder 192)
    - USO, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 522ab)
  - Revolutionary War
    - "Midnight Ride of Sybil Ludington", 1976 (Cabinet 8, Folder 432)
    - "Tryon's Raid", 1927 (Cabinet 8, Folder 435)
  - Veterans
    - Veteran Memorial Green, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 521d)
    - Wilton Bulletin Memorial Day Issue - Veteran supplement, 1999 (Cabinet 8, Folder MC11)
  - Women in War
    - "Heroes of the Home Front" - Civil War - Women’s contributions, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 523b)
    - Merwin, Jane Hyde - "Wilton Women in Revolutionary Days", 1902 (Cabinet 8, Folder 523a)